Aycock High School Photograph Collection PHC.218
State Archives of North Carolina
Aycock High School Photograph Collection
1940-1941
PHC.218
13 black and white photographic prints, various sizes ranging from approximately 5.5" x 3.5" to less than 1"x2". Photos were originally attached to two album pages, and most of the photos have been cropped, many into abstract shapes.
Aycock High School building exterior, teachers, and students of Aycock High School, probably class of 1940-1941.
Unknown
State Archives of North Carolina
Biographical/Historical
Aycock High School was in Cedar Grove (Orange County), NC, and was built in 1924. Students began attending the school in January of 1925, and the last class graduated in 1963.
Provenance
Collection donated September 2015 by Steve Massengill of Cary, NC.
Scope and Content
Photographs depicting the Aycock High School building front exterior, teachers, and students of Aycock High School, probably class of 1940-1941, Cedar Grove, NC. Photos were originally attached to two album pages, and most of the photos have been cropped, many into abstract shapes. Thirteen (13) black and white photographic prints, various sizes ranging from approximately 5.5" x 3.5" to less than 1"x2". Photos were originally attached to two album pages, and most of the photos have been cropped, many into abstract shapes.
Warren, V. L., Mrs.; Hughes, Alice; Hughes, E.; Pender, Irene; Cude, E. F.; McDade, Hazel; Wilson, Vergie; McDade, Curtis; Warren, Sue; Cobb, Roger; Yates, Mildred; Sartin, Henry; Anderson, Juanita; McDade, Paul
Aycock High School
Schools; Basketball; Teenagers; Women
Cedar Grove (N.C.); Orange County (N.C.)
- Overall exterior shot of the front of Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC. Four people are visible standing on the grounds in front of the school building; at least two appear to be students., c. 1940; PHC.218.01; Unknown
- Middle aged woman smiling and sitting on the front steps at the entrance to Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC. She is identified as Alice Hughes., c. 1940; PHC.218.02; Unknown
- Cropped photograph of a young woman in a coat with fur collar, hands in pockets of coat. She is identified as either E. Hughes or Mrs. V. L. Warren. Mrs. V. L. Warren was the Principal of Aycock High School from about 1926 until Spring of 1940., c. 1940; PHC.218.03; Unknown
- Cropped photograph of a young woman standing outdoors wearing a long coat and button down dress. Woman is identified as Irene Pender., c. 1940; PHC.218.04; Unknown
- Cropped photograph of a man wearing a dark suit and tie and seated outside. Man is identified as E. F. Cude., c. 1940; PHC.218.05; Unknown
- Cropped photograph of two unidentified young women standing side by side. This appears to have been cropped from a group shot that included others standing behind these two., c. 1940; PHC.218.06; Unknown
- Group photograph showing ten young people, men and women, possibly students, wearing a variety of costumes and standing in front of a brick wall and a small arching arbor docorated with flowers. Two of the men are wearing fezes from the Oasis Temple and several of the woman appear to be wearing flapper dresses and exagerated hats. One woman in the middle front is wearing all white and carrying a bushel basket. The group is identified, L-R: Hazel McDade, Clair McDade, Virgie Wilson, Curtis McDade, Sue Warren, Roger Cobb, Mildred Yates, Henry Sartin (?), Juanita Anderson, and Paul McDade., c. 1940; PHC.218.07; Unknown
- Group photograph of seven unidentified women wearing athletic uniforms (except one who is wearing a street dress) posed in front of a brick wall with what appears to be a basketball, probably a basketball team. Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC., c. 1940; PHC.218.08; Unknown
- Cropped group photograph showing five unidentified young men posing against a brick wall. Two wear Letter sweaters bearing a letter "A." Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC., c. 1940; PHC.218.09; Unknown
- Group photograph of twelve young unidentified woman wearing gym clothes (one is wearing street clothes) and posing with a basketball in front of a brick wall, likely a basketball team. Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC., c. 1940; PHC.218.10; Unknown
- Cropped group photograph of unidentified youg women wearing gym clothes and posing with a basketball on which has been inscribed "40," Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC. Photo has double exposure at right side., c. 1940; PHC.218.11; Unknown
- Cropped group photograph of boys' basketball team posing against brick wall with basketball inscribed "40," Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC., c. 1940; PHC.218.12; Unknown
- Group photograph of Aycock High School, Cedar Grove, NC, graduating class of either 1940 or 1941 posed on steps of the school in their caps and gowns. Child mascot is also shown and car in rear of shot., c. 1940; PHC.218.13; Unknown